<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Vincenzo goes to Datahood</title>
    <link>https://vincenzogalante.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Vincenzo goes to Datahood</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://vincenzogalante.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://vincenzogalante.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2023 12:46:15 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://vincenzogalante.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>DataTalksClub - Data Engineering Zoomcamp</title>
      <link>https://vincenzogalante.github.io/posts/dtc-data-engineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2023 12:46:15 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vincenzogalante.github.io/posts/dtc-data-engineering/</guid>
      <description>These last early mornings and late evenings have been filled with setting up my environment for the Data Engineering Zoomcamp.
My current setup involves a virtual machine, hosting a Postgres database, while being able to query it through pgAdmin - pulling it all up via docker-compose. Furthermore, I got to know the basics on how to set up the Google Cloud infrastructure via Terraform.
Within the next weeks, I will be working on workflow orchestration via Prefect, data warehousing in BigQuery, analytics engineering with DBT, and batch and stream processing with Kafka.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where to start?</title>
      <link>https://vincenzogalante.github.io/posts/where-to-start/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2023 17:28:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vincenzogalante.github.io/posts/where-to-start/</guid>
      <description>I wanted to learn more about data. How can data be stored? How do I get data from A to B? And how do I present data in a Dashboard? But where do you start when you have humanities complete knowledge at your fingertip?
I felt overwhelmed, and still do. And it is totally okay. We all need time to adjust and sort things out.
I started with the basics of the fundamental languages used for data jobs - SQL and Python.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First blog post ever</title>
      <link>https://vincenzogalante.github.io/posts/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 11:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vincenzogalante.github.io/posts/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>Hello out there, this is my first post.
This is the start of a wonderful learning journey full of ups and downs, new insights and learnings.
The name of this blog is based on the UK band &amp;ldquo;Frankie goes to Hollywood&amp;rdquo;.
So, relax, take a seat and enjoy the ride.
🎢</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://vincenzogalante.github.io/posts/about-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 10:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vincenzogalante.github.io/posts/about-me/</guid>
      <description>Hi there,
I am Vincenzo and this is my journey into Data.
From being a consultant for haute couture brands in Paris, to running strategic initiatives for the biggest european ecommerce platforms in Berlin - I already had some stations in my career.
Over the last years I learned how to think like a product manager and gained hands-on full stack web development skills, just to find my true passion now.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
